<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Educational material for LSU Programming Digital Media</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Educational material for LSU Programming Digital Media</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Arrange View Arrow Tools</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/arrange-view-arrow-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/arrange-view-arrow-tool/</guid>
      <description>The mouse tools allow direct interaction with Events, using the mouse. It is helpful to remember that actions done using the mouse tools can be undone at any time, so feel free to explore them. You can click the right mouse button in any open space in the Arrange or Edit views to open a list of mouse tools and editing commands. Choose the desired tool or command by clicking it with the left mouse button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arrange View Range Tools</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/arrange-view-range-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/arrange-view-range-tool/</guid>
      <description>The mouse tools allow direct interaction with Events, using the mouse. It is helpful to remember that actions done using the mouse tools can be undone at any time, so feel free to explore them. You can click the right mouse button in any open space in the Arrange or Edit views to open a list of mouse tools and editing commands. Choose the desired tool or command by clicking it with the left mouse button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arrange View Split Tools</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/arrange-view-split-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/arrange-view-split-tool/</guid>
      <description>Arrange View Mouse Tools The mouse tools allow direct interaction with Events, using the mouse. It is helpful to remember that actions done using the mouse tools can be undone at any time, so feel free to explore them. You can click the right mouse button in any open space in the Arrange or Edit views to open a list of mouse tools and editing commands. Choose the desired tool or command by clicking it with the left mouse button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio Event Transpose and Tune</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/audio-event-transpose-and-tune/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/audio-event-transpose-and-tune/</guid>
      <description>The ability to transpose and fine-tune audio adds a lot of flexibility when working with audio files. For instance, if you have a keyboard loop collection in which every loop is in the key of C, being able to transpose these loops to any other key opens up many possibilities.
In Studio One, transposing and tuning are a part of the same set of advanced algorithms as timestretching, so the quality is extremely high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Submission Instructions</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/basic-submission-instructions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/basic-submission-instructions/</guid>
      <description>This document provides basic instructions for DAW media management and submission procedures specific to our software and course management utilities.
The File Structure of a Studio One 3 Song Studio One 3 can create new Songs and new Projects.
This nomenclature varies from one DAW to the next.
Studio One 3 Projects can be thought of as mastering projects - a collection of multiple finished pieces that might form the basis for a full multi-song album or a feature film soundtrack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browsing for Instruments</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/browsing-for-instruments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/browsing-for-instruments/</guid>
      <description>Click on the Instruments tab in the Browser or press [F6] on the keyboard to browse your virtual instruments.
Sorting the Instruments View The list of virtual instruments can be sorted to help you find what you are looking for. Click on the Sort by options at the top of the Browser to sort by one of the following categories:
 Flat Sorts the instruments in alphabetical order in a continuous list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossfades</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/crossfades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/crossfades/</guid>
      <description>Crossfades are implementations of fades that smooth transitions between touching or overlapping audio regions. To make a crossfade, select one of two (or more) overlapping regions and press [X].
Once the crossfade is in place, you can adjust the shape and width by dragging the boundaries of the regions and/or the fade handles with the Arrow Tool.
Generally, shorter crossfades work well for percussive material (e.g. drums, short guitar strums) while longer crossfades work on more resonant or sustained material (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cut Copy and Paste</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/copying-and-pasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/copying-and-pasting/</guid>
      <description>As with most software applications, Studio One supports cut, copy, and paste actions. Once you have selected an Event or a range of Events, you can perform these actions:
 Cut Press [Ctrl]/[Cmd]+[X] on the keyboard to cut the current selection. Copy Press [Ctrl]/[Cmd]+[C] on the keyboard to copy the current selection. Paste Once a selection is cut or copied, press [Ctrl]/[Cmd]+[P] on the keyboard to paste the selection. The Events are pasted on the selected Track, at the current playback cursor position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duplicating</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/duplicating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/duplicating/</guid>
      <description>The Duplicate action essentially combines the Copy and Paste actions and intelligently places the pasted selection based on the musical timing of the selection in the Song. Choose Duplicate in the Edit menu or press [D] on the keyboard to duplicate the current selection. The duplicated Event is always placed after the original Event, and it is automatically selected once duplicated. As with the other editing actions, Duplicate can apply to any number of currently selected Events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project</title>
      <link>/computer-music/projects/final-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/projects/final-project/</guid>
      <description>Description For your final project, you will compose a 3:00-5:00 original piece to be presented at the end-of-semester concert on Wednesday April 25. This project will be based in some manner on an original field recording – e.g. something you recorded in a coffee shop, while walking around campus, or an interesting collection of sounds from your kitchen. Otherwise, the form and genre of the project is completely up to you, so long as it can be presented in some format at the concert and uploaded to the class SoundCloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project Rubric</title>
      <link>/computer-music/rubrics/final-project-rubric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/rubrics/final-project-rubric/</guid>
      <description>Final Project Student&amp;rsquo;s Name: Points: /25 Grade:     1 3 5 Score     Sound Design Poor quality, homogenous, uninteresting, and/or pulled from prohibited sources. Sufficient quality, moderate variety, and/or sourced appropriately. High quality, exceptionally varied and interesting, covers a wide timbral/tonal range.    Editing and Automation Techniques Little and/or incorrect use of editing techniques. Moderate and mostly correct use of editing techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generic Lab Rubric</title>
      <link>/computer-music/rubrics/generic-lab-rubric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/rubrics/generic-lab-rubric/</guid>
      <description>Rubric Lab Assignment Student&amp;rsquo;s Name: Points: /10 Grade:     1 3 5 Score     Instructions Failed to complete most of the required steps. Completed most of the required steps. Completed all of the required steps.    General Technical Merit Several errors made in mixing, bouncing, and/or submitting. One or two errors made in mixing, bouncing, and/or submitting. No errors made in mixing, bouncing, and/or submitting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guided Listening Presentation</title>
      <link>/computer-music/presentation/guided-listening-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/presentation/guided-listening-presentation/</guid>
      <description>These presentations will be prepared and presented in randomly assigned groups of 2-3 students. They should be approximately 10 minutes long. Half of this time is dedicated to listening to the full piece. There are two components to this assignment, each with different different due dates (noted below).
Song Selection – DUE WEDNESDAY FEB 21 (see separate poll on Moodle) Chose a song from the shared class Spotify Presentation Selections playlist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guided Listening Presentation Rubric</title>
      <link>/computer-music/rubrics/guided-listening-presentation-rubric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/rubrics/guided-listening-presentation-rubric/</guid>
      <description>Rubric Guided Listening Presentation Group: Student&amp;rsquo;s Name(s): Points: /100 Grade:    Category Description Score     Song Selection Timely response to song selection forum on Moodle (due Sept 20). /10   Intro and Background Info Cited background information on song and/or artist to help contextualize the work for the audience. /25   &amp;ldquo;Listen For&amp;rdquo; A quick preemptive summary to prepare the audience for what they are about to hear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/impact/</guid>
      <description>Impact features a grid of pads into which samples are loaded and played back independently, as with many popular hardware drum-sample players. Each pad has its own pitch, amplifier, and filter controls with accompanying envelopes. There are multiple stereo and mono outputs for each pad, making sophisticated output busing simple.
Interface Impact is arranged as a 4x4 grid of pads, with controls for each pad. Below each pad are Solo and Mute controls, as well as an Output Channel assignment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import Video</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/import-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/import-video/</guid>
      <description>The simplest way to import a video file is to drag-and-drop it from the File Browser into the arrangement. Supported video files appear in the browser with a Film Strip icon. You can also use the Import Video menu in the Video Player to import any supported video file.
Drag a video file from the File Browser to the arrangement to import the video file to the Video Player. When doing this, note that the position to which you drag the video is used to set the offset for video playback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LSU - MUS 2745 Syllabus</title>
      <link>/computer-music/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Computer Music Course Syllabus — Fall 2017          Class Times M/W 9:30-10:20am, F 9:30-10:20am &amp;amp; TBD   Classrooms MDA 248, SoM203 (lab), DMC Studio (as needed)   Instructor Eric Sheffield esheff1@lsu.edu   Office Hours M 10:30-11:30, SoM 203   Supervising Professor Dr. Jesse Allison jtallison@lsu.edu   Final Concert Monday April 24, 2017, 4:00pm, LSU SoM Recital Hall   Final Exam Monday May 1, 2017, 10:00am-12:00pm, MDA248    Objectives Blah blah</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Assignment 2</title>
      <link>/computer-music/lab-assignments/lab-assignment-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/lab-assignments/lab-assignment-2/</guid>
      <description>Recording and Importing Audio Files Prerequisites Content from Lab Assignment 1
Preparation of a mobile audio recording app of your choice on your personal mobile device:
 Select and install an app that has the ability to record uncompressed audio - this includes wav, aiff, Apple Lossless, FLAC or caf files. Apps that record only in mp3 or AAC are prohibited. Test recording of uncompressed audio. Test file transfer from mobile device to computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Assignment 3</title>
      <link>/computer-music/lab-assignments/lab-assignment-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/lab-assignments/lab-assignment-3/</guid>
      <description>Crossfades, Automation, and Using the Mixer Prerequisites Content from Lab Assignment 1
Content from Lab Assignment 2
Create personal free account at Freesound.org
Optional: Explore Freesound.org and the University of Iowa Musical Instrument Samples repository for interesting samples
Review the following document from our course materials:
 Basic Submission Instructions  Objectives:  Crossfades Introduction to the Mixer/Console Volume and Pan Automation   Create a duplicate of your project from Lab Assignment 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Assignment 4</title>
      <link>/computer-music/lab-assignments/lab-assignment-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/lab-assignments/lab-assignment-4/</guid>
      <description>Video Workflow There will not be any files to submit for this lab. We will consider it a work day to familiarize yourself with a Video Workflow process in preparation for Mini Composition 2. You do not have to use the exact procedure outlined for this exercise. However, the steps described below use software already available to you in the SoM203 lab. Your primary objective should be to work through all of the sections below and approach the instructor if you need further instructions or clarifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Assignment 5</title>
      <link>/computer-music/lab-assignments/lab-assignment-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/lab-assignments/lab-assignment-5/</guid>
      <description>Basic MIDI Recording Prerequisites Content from all previous lab assignments
The Grid in the Studio One Reference Manual
Recommended - review the following sections in the Studio One Reference Manual:
 Loops Tab Browsing for Instruments (in Instruments and Audio Effects) All Built-In Virtual Instruments - especially Mojito and Mai Tai Metronome Control  Optional - Set Up MIDI Keyboards in the Studio One Reference Manual Our MIDI controllers in the lab have already been properly set up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Assignment 6</title>
      <link>/computer-music/lab-assignments/lab-assignment-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/lab-assignments/lab-assignment-6/</guid>
      <description>Synthesizers Objectives: Exploring Mojito and Mai Tai virtual instruments.
 Open your DAW, create a new song/project with the title &amp;ldquo;YourFirstNameYourLastName-Lab6&amp;rdquo;. If prompted, use the following settings:   Sample Rate - 44.1kHz Resolution - 16 bit   Open the Studio One Reference Manual under the Help menu. Navigate to Built-In Virtual Instruments and read the entry for Mojito. Open the Instruments tab of the Browser panel. Drag an instance of the Mojito instrument onto a new track in the Arrange window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Assignment 7</title>
      <link>/computer-music/lab-assignments/lab-assignment-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/lab-assignments/lab-assignment-7/</guid>
      <description>Advanced MIDI and Automation Objectives: MIDI quantization editing
 swing humanize manual adjustment Synth parameter automation   Open your DAW, create a new song/project with the title &amp;ldquo;YourFirstNameYourLastName-Lab7&amp;rdquo;. If prompted, use the following settings:   Sample Rate - 44.1kHz Resolution - 16 bit Tempo - your choice (try to get away from 120)   Open the Instruments tab of the Browser panel. Drag an instance of the Impact sampler instrument onto a new track in the Arrange window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Assignment 8</title>
      <link>/computer-music/lab-assignments/lab-assignment-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/lab-assignments/lab-assignment-8/</guid>
      <description>Plugins and Advanced Mixing Objectives:  Practice with Plugins as inserts Practice with routing and use of plugins on a submix/bus Practice with routing and use of plugins on an aux send  All of the steps below can be done in an existing project (e.g. your Final Project rough draft) or a new, simple project using anything from prepackaged loops to newly recorded MIDI parts. Regardless of where you start, please ensure that your song/project has the title &amp;ldquo;YourFirstNameYourLastName-Lab8&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loops Tab</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/loops-tab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/loops-tab/</guid>
      <description>The Loops tab lets you locate and explore audio and music loop content made for Studio One in the Browser, with intelligent sorting to assist you in finding the right loops quickly and easily. Click on the Loops tab in the Browser or press [F8] on the keyboard to browse through any installed loop content.
Sorting Loops The Loops tab offers a three-tiered sorting system. At the top of the Loops tab window, you&amp;rsquo;ll see Sort by&amp;hellip; followed by three category selectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manual Timestretching</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/manual-timestretching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/manual-timestretching/</guid>
      <description>With manual timestretching, you can stretch an Audio Event independently of the Song tempo or audio file tempo.
To manually stretch an Audio Event with the Arrow tool, float the mouse cursor to the edge of the target Audio Event and hold [Alt]/[Option] on the keyboard. The Timestretch tool appears, allowing you to click on the edge of the Event and drag left or right to timestretch the Event, making it shorter or longer In this case, the length of the Event changes, using the Speedup factor, but the pitch of the audio the Event contains remains the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metronome Control</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/metronome-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/metronome-control/</guid>
      <description>A metronome makes audible clicks or other sounds that correspond to beats at a selectable tempo, providing the musicians with a tempo reference while recording. This is especially useful when recording drums or other rhythm-intensive tracks, as the editing and arranging processes are made much easier when the recorded audio lines up with musical bars and beats.
In Studio One, the metronome can be engaged and disengaged both globally and for each hardware output in the Console, including the Main Out and any Sub Outs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini Composition 1</title>
      <link>/computer-music/projects/mini-composition-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/projects/mini-composition-1/</guid>
      <description>Musique Concrète Narrative Description For this project, you will compose a 1:00-2:00 piece using techniques from the Musique Concrète tradition that tells a story through sound. The composition should take the listener through an activity, scene, emotion, or environment without the aid of spoken word. It should also have a coherent formal structure, with a clear beginning and ending.
 Only use audio samples (no virtual instruments). The source audio material for the composition may be retrieved from an online repository such as Freesound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini Composition 1 Rubric</title>
      <link>/computer-music/rubrics/mini-composition-1-rubric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/rubrics/mini-composition-1-rubric/</guid>
      <description>Mini Composition 1 - Musique Concrète Narrative Student&amp;rsquo;s Name: Points: /20 Grade:     1 3 5 Score     Audio Samples Poor quality, homogenous, uninteresting, and/or pulled from prohibited sources. Sufficient quality, moderate variety, and/or sourced appropriately. High quality, exceptionally varied and interesting, covers a wide timbral/tonal range. Use of original recordings.    Editing and Automation Techniques Little and/or incorrect use of editing techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini Composition 2</title>
      <link>/computer-music/projects/mini-composition-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/projects/mini-composition-2/</guid>
      <description>Synthesizer Film Soundtrack Description For this project, you will compose a 1:00-2:00 soundtrack for a short film using primarily the synthesizer instruments in your DAW. The composition can include any combination of background music, foreground music, and/or sound effects. It should also have a coherent formal structure, with a clear beginning and ending. The video can be any selection of your choosing - including footage sourced from YouTube, archive.org, or something you shoot and edit yourself - but it must be properly edited and combined with your soundtrack audio file before submitting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini Composition 2 Rubric</title>
      <link>/computer-music/rubrics/mini-composition-2-rubric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/rubrics/mini-composition-2-rubric/</guid>
      <description>Mini Composition 2 - Synthesizer Film Soundtrack Student&amp;rsquo;s Name: Points: /20 Grade:     1 3 5 Score     Synthesizers Little to no timbral variety, insufficient track/instrument quantity, use of prohibited instruments. Moderate timbral variety, sufficient track/instrument quantity, no use of prohibited instruments. Extensive timbral variety, exceeds required track/instrument quantity, covers a wide timbral/tonal range, no use of prohibited instruments    MIDI and Automation Techniques Little and/or incorrect use of MIDI quantization, MIDI recording/editing, and/or automation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixing Down</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/mixing-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/mixing-down/</guid>
      <description>In most cases, you’ll record multiple Tracks in a Song, but you&amp;rsquo;ll need to mix these Tracks to a stereo format for distribution on CD, DVD, or the Web. With a DAW such as Studio One, this simply means saving your mix to a stereo file.
Create a Mixdown To create a mix of your Song in Studio One, navigate to Song/Export Mixdown or press [Ctrl]/[Cmd]+[E] on the keyboard to open the Export Mixdown menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mojito</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/mojito/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/mojito/</guid>
      <description>Mojito is a simple, monophonic, subtractive synthesizer with effects that is capable of generating a wide range of sounds. It models a classic analog synthesizer and features a low-aliasing oscillator and a 24 dB filter emulation. Mojito can generate killer bass sounds, lead sounds, and special effects.
Interface Mojito is organized into Oscillator (OSC), Amplifier (AMP), Filter (FLT), and FX sections, with easy-to-use, yet powerful controls.
Oscillator Mojito’s Oscillator section is on the upper left of the plug-in window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Selections</title>
      <link>/computer-music/presentation/music-selections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/presentation/music-selections/</guid>
      <description>Spotify Full Playlist Link https://open.spotify.com/user/1228893326/playlist/5qrOAfJ87Jx43FpHMaJJoY
   Artist Album Track Title Link     Amon Tobin ISAM Lost &amp;amp; Found https://open.spotify.com/track/1crZjm3JxiLcDGv1ecWjaS   Aphex Twin Computer Controlled Acoustic Instruments pt2 EP DISKPREPT1 https://open.spotify.com/track/1HrFCfD6GjKWjtLaN7NFFR   Aphex Twin Syro 4 bit 9d api+e+6 [126.26] https://open.spotify.com/track/3NK7KFnTh3rKCgUvsKIDfi   Autechre Exai prac-f https://open.spotify.com/track/59qW6i10bp4uRrMxXKq7JZ   Björk Medúlla Who Is It https://open.spotify.com/track/1slmImGr63SFOlmHKe1yM2   The Books Lost And Safe Be Good To Them Always https://open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naming Tracks</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/naming-tracks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/naming-tracks/</guid>
      <description>The name for a track can be set immediately when the track is created.
If the track was automatically named (for example, when a track is created by dragging-and-dropping an instrument or audio file), it can be renamed by double-clicking on the name in the Track Inspector or Track Column to the left of the Arrange Window.
Track Inspector:
Track Column:
Images reproduced from the official Studio One Version 3.3.0 Reference Manual</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on DAW instructions</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/notes-on-daw-instructions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/notes-on-daw-instructions/</guid>
      <description>Notes on DAW Instructions Since all modern mainstream DAW software comes with sufficient documentation from the manufacturer, we have taken an approach that utilizes as much content from the official manuals as possible. This documentation can be supplemented as needed with additional online content, visual aids, in-class demonstrations, and more at the instructor&amp;rsquo;s discretion.
For this example course content based on PreSonus&amp;rsquo; Studio One 3, small sections of the Studio One 3 Reference Manual have been duplicated, with proper attribution, in separate Markdown files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reversing Audio Event</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/reversing-audio-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/reversing-audio-event/</guid>
      <description>There are two ways to easily reverse the content in an Audio Event:
 Right-click [Ctrl+click on some Macs] on an Audio Event. In the menu that appears, hover over &amp;ldquo;Audio: Operations specific to audio events&amp;rdquo;, then select &amp;ldquo;Reverse Audio&amp;rdquo;. With the desired Audio Event already selected, use the key command [Cmd+R] on Mac, [Ctrl+R] on Windows.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up MIDI Keyboards</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/setup-midi-keyboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/setup-midi-keyboards/</guid>
      <description>A MIDI keyboard controller is a hardware MIDI device that is generally used for playing and controlling other MIDI devices, virtual software instruments, and software parameters. In Studio One, these devices are referred to as Keyboards. Before recording a performance with a Keyboard, the MIDI keyboard controller must first be set up in Studio One. Once a Keyboard is set up, it is available at all times for use in Studio One.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strip Silence</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/strip-silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/strip-silence/</guid>
      <description>It is quite common that, as the result of continuous recording, some Audio Events may have gaps of silence or relatively low levels between performances. It may be helpful in these cases to remove the gaps and only keep the desired sections of the recorded Event. Studio One&amp;rsquo;s Strip Silence function, controlled from the Strip Silence panel, is designed to handle this task.
Open the Strip Silence panel by clicking on the Strip Silence button in the toolbar, or select Strip Silence from the View/Additional Views menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Console</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/console-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/console-intro/</guid>
      <description>Mixing in Studio One is primarily done in the Console. Open the Console by clicking on the [Mix] button or by pressing [F3] on the keyboard.
Each channel of audio in your Song is represented by a Channel in the Console. Audio Tracks in the Arrange view are directly represented by Audio Channels in the Console, whereas Instrument Tracks have no direct representation in the Console. Instead, Instrument Channels represent the audio output of virtual instruments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grid</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/the-grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/the-grid/</guid>
      <description>The Arrangement grid is comprised of the ticks in the timeline and the vertical lines extending from those ticks through the background of the Arrangement. This grid uses the Timebase setting as the basis for its display. The Timebase settings are Seconds, Samples, Bars, and Frames, and they determine the behavior of Event and tool snapping. The Timebase can be changed at any time, without directly affecting the arrangement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume and Pan Automation</title>
      <link>/computer-music/daw-instructions/volume-and-pan-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/daw-instructions/volume-and-pan-automation/</guid>
      <description>What is Automation? Automation lets you record changes in parameter values; thereafter, Studio One can perform these value changes for you. For instance, you can record level changes in a Track by capturing your fader movements during playback; from then on, Studio One can perform the level changes.
Before the advent of automation, mixing was very much a performance. Sometimes it took many pairs of hands on the mixing console to accomplish all of the fader, mute, solo, and other movements to achieve a mix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/computer-music/markdown-cheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/markdown-cheatsheet/</guid>
      <description>This is intended as a quick reference and showcase. For more complete info, see John Gruber&amp;rsquo;s original spec and the Github-flavored Markdown info page.
Note that there is also a Cheatsheet specific to Markdown Here if that&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for. You can also check out more Markdown tools.
Table of Contents Headers
Emphasis
Lists
Links
Images
Code and Syntax Highlighting
Tables
Blockquotes
Inline HTML
Horizontal Rule
Line Breaks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/computer-music/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/readme/</guid>
      <description>Intro To Computer Music Blah Blah Blah
See our notes on creating your own custom DAW instructions.
change</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/computer-music/to-dos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/to-dos/</guid>
      <description> To-dos open source license for course? add assignment descriptions to rubrics revise basic DAW instructions (base off of lab assignments) create &amp;ldquo;best practices&amp;rdquo; document revise lab assignment descriptions so that they work more generally 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8  make sampler instrument lab insert images revise instructions mini comp 1 mini comp 2 final project basic DAW page guided listening presentation  rubrics mini comp 1 mini comp 2 final project labs (one for all)  choose pieces for analysis presentation resources for analysis unit put in proper link tags figure out actual TODO formatting look for Pat Metheny robot orchestra add sampler instrument lab check out the following for music selections Xenakis concrete ph look at 60 X 60 for music selections   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Music Unit 1</title>
      <link>/computer-music/lab-assignments/general-music-unit-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/lab-assignments/general-music-unit-1/</guid>
      <description>General Music Unit 1 Basic Theory
Pitch (from a scientific perspective)
The overtone Series
Scales: C major, F major, G major
 Solfege Why 7 letters and 12 notes Introduction to key signatures  Intervals
 Half steps and whole steps  Harmony
 Major triads Minor triads  Intro to Reading and Writing Music
Rhythm
 Quarter, half, whole, equivalent rests Exercise: https://www.musictheory.net/exercises  Pitch
 Staff (lines and spaces) Treble Clef Exercise: have students make their own acronyms for lines and spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Music Unit 1</title>
      <link>/music-fundamentals/general-music-unit-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/music-fundamentals/general-music-unit-1/</guid>
      <description>General Music Unit 1 Basic Theory
Pitch (from a scientific perspective)
The overtone Series
Scales: C major, F major, G major
 Solfege Why 7 letters and 12 notes Introduction to key signatures  Intervals
 Half steps and whole steps  Harmony
 Major triads Minor triads  Intro to Reading and Writing Music
Rhythm
 Quarter, half, whole, equivalent rests Exercise: https://www.musictheory.net/exercises  Pitch
 Staff (lines and spaces) Treble Clef Exercise: have students make their own acronyms for lines and spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Music Unit 2</title>
      <link>/computer-music/lab-assignments/general-music-unit-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/lab-assignments/general-music-unit-2/</guid>
      <description>General Music Unit 2 Intermediate Theory
Scales
 All 12 major scales Introduction to minor scales All 12 key signatures  Intervals
 All intervals within the octave  Harmony
 All major and minor triads Seventh Chords Chord progressions  V I relationship Diatonic chords Tonic, dominant, subdominant Circle of fifths Blues form I vi ii V progression (and typical substitutions)  Introduction to roman numeral analysis  Intermediate Reading and Writing Music</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Music Unit 2</title>
      <link>/music-fundamentals/general-music-unit-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/music-fundamentals/general-music-unit-2/</guid>
      <description>General Music Unit 2 Intermediate Theory
Scales
 All 12 major scales Introduction to minor scales All 12 key signatures  Intervals
 All intervals within the octave  Harmony
 All major and minor triads Seventh Chords Chord progressions  V I relationship Diatonic chords Tonic, dominant, subdominant Circle of fifths Blues form I vi ii V progression (and typical substitutions)  Introduction to roman numeral analysis  Intermediate Reading and Writing Music</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Music Unit 3</title>
      <link>/computer-music/lab-assignments/general-music-unit-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/lab-assignments/general-music-unit-3/</guid>
      <description>General Music Unit 3 Advanced Theory
Scales:
 All 12 major and minor scales  modes of major scale  Symmetrical scales  Diminished Whole tone Augmented Others Introduction to 12 tone and atonal music  Intervals
 All intervals within the octave including extensions (ie 9ths, 11ths, 13ths, and alterations)   Harmony
 All major and minor seventh chords Introduction to chord extensions Chord progressions  Substitutions for common chord progressions Secondary dominants and modulation Circle of fifths continued Examples of non-functional harmony  Advanced roman numeral analysis  Examples from classical, jazz and popular music   Advanced Reading and Writing Music</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Music Unit 3</title>
      <link>/music-fundamentals/general-music-unit-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/music-fundamentals/general-music-unit-3/</guid>
      <description>General Music Unit 3 Advanced Theory
Scales:
 All 12 major and minor scales  modes of major scale  Symmetrical scales  Diminished Whole tone Augmented Others Introduction to 12 tone and atonal music  Intervals
 All intervals within the octave including extensions (ie 9ths, 11ths, 13ths, and alterations)   Harmony
 All major and minor seventh chords Introduction to chord extensions Chord progressions  Substitutions for common chord progressions Secondary dominants and modulation Circle of fifths continued Examples of non-functional harmony  Advanced roman numeral analysis  Examples from classical, jazz and popular music   Advanced Reading and Writing Music</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gibber</title>
      <link>/computer-music/lab-assignments/gibber/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/lab-assignments/gibber/</guid>
      <description>Gibber Gibber is a creative coding environment for audiovisual performance and composition. It contains features for audio synthesis and musical sequencing, 2d drawing, 3d scene construction and manipulation, and live-coding shaders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Assignment 1</title>
      <link>/computer-music/lab-assignments/lab-assignment-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/lab-assignments/lab-assignment-1/</guid>
      <description>Basic Audio Editing and Intro to DAW Prerequisites Review the following sections in the Studio One Reference Manual:
 Fundamentals&amp;gt;Drag-and-Drop Fundamentals&amp;gt;Transport Controls Editing&amp;gt;Events Editing&amp;gt;The Grid Optional but recommended:  Editing&amp;gt;Arrange View Mouse Tools Editing&amp;gt;Common Editing Actions   Review the following document from our course materials:
 [Basic Submission Instructions](/computer-music/daw-instructions/basic-submission-instructions/)  Objectives  Introduction to Event-based audio editing techniques and tools within the arrange window  Splicing with the [Split Tool](/computer-music/daw-instructions/arrange-view-split-tool/) Selecting, Moving, and Resizing with the [Arrow Tool](/computer-music/daw-instructions/arrange-view-arrow-tool/) and/or [Range Tool](/computer-music/daw-instructions/arrange-view-range-tool/) [Copying and Pasting](/computer-music/daw-instructions/copying-and-pasting/) and/or [Duplicating](/computer-music/daw-instructions/duplicating/) Events  Introduction to Event-based audio processing within the arrange window  [Reversing Audio](/computer-music/daw-instructions/reversing-audio-event/) [Pitch Shifting](/computer-music/daw-instructions/audio-event-transpose-and-tune/) [Speed](/computer-music/daw-instructions/manual-timestretching/)  Basic DAW arrange window tasks  [Naming tracks](/computer-music/daw-instructions/naming-tracks/) Working with audio events Importing audio files with Drag-and-Drop   Instructions  Download DrumLoop1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unit Breakdown draft </title>
      <link>/computer-music/unit-breakdown-draft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/computer-music/unit-breakdown-draft/</guid>
      <description>Unit Breakdown Draft Revised 7&amp;frasl;6 Approximately 15 weeks  Sound Basics
 Noise Continuum Frequency (Pitch) Intensity (Amplitude) Tone Quality/Timbre Basic Waveform Types  Digital Audio Basics
 Bit Depth and Sample Rate ADC/DAC Limitations, Artifacts, and Other Characteristics Nyquist Aliasing Storage Clipping  The Studio as a Compositional Tool
 Musique Concrète and Tape-Based Music
Culminates in Mini Composition 1
 Analysis
 MIDI
 Synths
 Microphones</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>test</title>
      <link>/music-fundamentals/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/music-fundamentals/test/</guid>
      <description>HIIII jalsdjf;lj</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>